Joyce Shen

joyceshen.me / joyceshen0@gmail.com

Passionate product designer with over 2 years of experience working in cross-functional teams to conduct user research and design strategic products for clients. Team player with strong communication skills, outside-the-box ideas, user-centered thinking, and an eye for detail.

Experience

UI/UX Design Co-op / U.S. Bank

August 2022 - Present / Atlanta, GA

Researched, designed, and tested emerging banking technologies under The Greenhouse Innovation Lab

Design Bootcamp Instructor / Bits of Good

June 2022 - Present / Atlanta, GA

Led lectures, prepared curriculum, and provided individual guidance to product design learners

Design Intern / Roblox

May 2022 - August 2022 / San Mateo, CA

- Presented a short- and long-term design vision for collaboration in game creation, guided by findings from leading user interviews, surveys, usability tests, and stakeholder meetings
- Led design support for an improved file management tool that was released to Roblox's 8+ million game creators

UX Design Intern / Lacework

May 2021 - August 2021 / San Jose, CA

- Redesigned a workflow for creating cloud security reports, used by thousands of security executives
- Overhauled Lacework's dark mode design system, ensuring compliance with accessibility standards

Product Designer / Bits of Good

January 2021 - Present / Atlanta, GA

- Collaborated in cross-functional teams to develop powerful web apps for nonprofits advancing social good
- Solutions have benefited children of incarcerated mothers, thousands of university students, and nonprofit leaders

UI & Digital Coordinator / EFBA

June 2020 - November 2020 / San Francisco, CA

• Drove design and implementation of a new staff portal, a website log-in system, and informational webpages

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology / BS Computer Science

August 2019 - May 2023 / Atlanta, GA

4.0 GPA, Faculty Honors / Concentrations: People and Media

Skills

Design	Tools	Code
UI Design	Figma	JavaScript
User Experience Design	Sketch	HTML + CSS
User Research	Adobe XD	Java
User Testing	Adobe Photoshop	С
Wireframes + Prototypes	Confluence	Python
Design Systems	Asana	React